Baba...
爸爸
Yes, my son.
什么事 儿子
Tell me a story.
跟我讲个故事吧
Which one?
什么故事
The story of home.
关于家乡的故事
Millions of years ago...
数百万年前
a meteorite made of vibranium...
一块振金陨石撞向地球
the strongest substance in the universe...
振金是宇宙中最为坚硬的物质
struck the continent of Africa...
陨石最终落在了非洲大陆上..
affecting the plant life around it.
影响改变了周围的植被
And when the time of man came...
待到人类的时代来临
five tribes settled on it and called it Wakanda.
五个部落定居在此并称此地为 瓦坎达
The tribes lived in constant war with each other...
这些部落之间经常爆发战争
until a warrior shaman...
直到一位战斗巫师
received a vision from the Panther Goddess Bast...
见到了来自黑豹女神芭丝特的幻影
who led him to the Heart-Shaped Herb...
引领他找到了心形草
a plant that granted him
一种能赋予他超越人类的力量
superhuman strength, speed and instincts.
速度和直觉的植物
The warrior became king...
这名勇士成为了国王...
and the first Black Panther...
也是第一代黑豹
the protector of Wakanda.
瓦坎达的守护者
Four tribes agreed to live under the king's rule...
四个部落都接受了国王的统治
but the Jabari Tribe isolated themselves in the mountains.
只有贾巴里部落孤居在雪岭之间
The Wakandans used vibranium to develop technology...
瓦坎达人民利用振金发展科技
more advanced than any other nation.
比全世界所有国家都先进
But as Wakanda thrived...
然而随着瓦坎达的崛起
the world around it descended further into chaos.
它周围的世界却陷入了更深的混乱
To keep vibranium safe...
为了保证振金的安全
the Wakandans vowed to hide in plain sight...
瓦坎达人民决意要隐匿于世
keeping the truth of their power
不向外界展露
from the outside world.
他们真实的力量
And we still hide, Baba?
我们还在潜伏么 爸爸
Yes.
是的
Why?
为什么
1992年
奥 克 兰
加 利 福 尼 亚
翻译
CJ 阿微 Cecilia 饽饽 ArthurBoxEr 丛林的鱼
杜初晨  书包没啦拉链呦  小草莓  BrookDee
翻译
Emma 胡帅颖 二傻 伊冯波波娜 Zero Ren
校对
william2568  rix  我问这瓜保熟么
- Lucky shot! - That ain't lucky!
- 运气球  - 才不是运气
特效
云中漫步wfaith
Whatever! Get outta here!
- 随便吧  - 一边去
Check up.
注意
Pick your man up! He open.
过来 防守他
Where you at?
怎么着
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
快上  快上  快上
Pass! Pass!
传球 传球
- Got you, E. - E, hurry up!
- 我就知道 - 快点啊
Watch me get this.
看我的
Tim Hardaway style. That's what I call it, baby.
蒂姆•哈达威流  这招就该这么叫
Come on.
来啊
What you got?
你怎么样
You ain't got nothing.
你拿我没辙
Hey, look, if we get in and out quick,
听着 我们只要保证快进快出
won't be no worries.
就没什么好担心的
You in the van, come in through from the west.
你开车从西边过来
Come around the corner.
转到街角处
- Land right here. - Mmm-hmm.
就停在这
Me and the twins are pulling up right here.
我跟双胞胎把车停在这
We're leaving this car behind, okay? We come this...
这车就不要了 明白吗 我们从这儿…
Hide the straps.
把枪收起来
Yo, is it the Feds?
是警察吗
No.
不是
It's these two Grace Jones-looking chicks.
两个长得和格蕾丝•琼斯一样的妞
They're holding spears.
还带着矛
Open it.
开门
You serious?
你确定？
They won't knock again.
她们下次就不是敲门了
Who are you?
你是谁
Prince N'Jobu, son of Azzuri.
恩乔布王子  阿祖里之子
Prove to me you are one of us.
向我证明你是我们的一员
My King.
陛下
Leave us.
退下
This is James. I trust him with my life. He stays...
这是詹姆斯 我以生命担保他值得信任 他可以留下
with your permission, King T'Chaka.
只要您允许的话  特查卡国王
As you wish.
如你所愿
At ease.
起来吧
Come, baby brother.
过来  兄弟
Let me see how you are holding up.
让我看看你过得怎样
You look strong.
看你体格很棒嘛
Glory to Bast, I am in good health.
女神保佑 我很健康
How is home?
家里怎么样？
Not so good.
不怎么样
Baby brother.
兄弟
There has been an attack.
我们家乡遭到了袭击
This man...
这个人...
Ulysses Klaue...
叫尤利西斯•克劳...
尤利西斯•克劳  出身于军人家庭 父亲在二战时为纳粹工作  克劳长大后成
为物理学家 在荷兰钻研声音科学 发明了能把声音转换成图像的装置 由于
克劳需要振金来增强威力 于是来到瓦坎达寻找振金
stole a quarter ton of vibranium from us...
偷了我们0.25吨的振金
and triggered a bomb at the border to escape.
为了逃跑 他还在边境地区引爆了炸弹
Many lives were lost.
我们死伤惨重
He knew where we hid the vibranium...
他知道我们藏置振金的地点...
and how to strike.
也知道如何有效发动袭击
He had someone on the inside.
他有内应
Why are you here?
那你来这里做什么？
Because I want you to look me in the eyes...
因为我想让你看着我的眼睛
and tell me why you betrayed Wakanda.
告诉我你为什么要背叛瓦坎达
I did no such thing.
我没有背叛祖国
Tell him who you are.
告诉他你是谁
Zuri, son of Badu...
巴杜之子 祖瑞
What?
什么？
James. James, you lied to me?
詹姆斯 詹姆斯 你骗了我？
Leave him.
放开他
You were Wakandan this whole time?
你一直都是瓦坎达人的卧底？
You betrayed Wakanda!
你背叛了瓦坎达
How could you lie to me like...
你怎么可以欺骗我？
Stand down.
住手
Did you think that you were the only spy we sent here?
你以为我们只派了你一个间谍到这里吗？
Prince N'Jobu...
恩乔布王子
you will return home at once...
我命令你即刻回国...
where you will face the Council...
你将会面对议会的质询
and inform them of your crimes.
并向他们坦白你的罪行
Check up!
开球吧
Guard your man, guard your man!
防好你的人 防好你的人
漫 威
影业
现 在
The tiny nation of Wakanda
非洲小国瓦坎达正举行全国哀悼
is mourning the death of its monarch, King T'Chaka.
逝世的特查卡国王
The beloved ruler was one of many confirmed dead...
一周前 这位深受爱戴的统治者
after a terrorist attack
在联合国总部
at the United Nations a week ago.
的恐怖袭击中丧生
The suspect has since been apprehended.
他是众多遇难者中的一位
BBC 环球新闻
瓦坎达国王
Though it remains one of
嫌疑人现已被逮捕
the poorest countries in the world...
即使瓦坎达是世界上最穷的国家之一
fortified by mountain ranges...
国内山峦起伏
and an impenetrable rainforest...
雨林密布
Wakanda does not engage
但该国从未参与过国际贸易
in international trade or accept aid.
也从未接受过国际援助
The succession of the throne...
继承该国王位的人
is expected to fall to the oldest of the king's two children...
会是前国王的长子
Prince T'Challa.
也就是特查拉王子
特查拉 有着超人的智慧和领袖气质 而且格斗技术超高 在自己的国家瓦坎达 他面
临一切内忧外患  作为年轻的王位继承人 各方势力对于王位的觊觎 外界对瓦坎达
振金矿的虎视眈眈 都是他急需解决的问题 必须背负起家庭和国家的重任
My Prince...
王子殿下...
coming up on them now.
我们就要到达他们上空了
萨姆比萨森林
尼日利亚
No need, Okoye. I can handle this alone.
没事的 奥克耶 我自己能解决
奥克耶 皇家护卫队队长 黑豹的亲信 国防指挥官的所爱 在埃里克与国防
指挥官对外宣战做准备时 以出人意料的方式成功救场
Hmm.
嗯
I will get Nakia out as quickly as possible.
我会尽快把娜奇雅救出来
Just don't freeze when you see her.
你见到她时 不要愣住就好
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
I never freeze.
我可不会愣
What's going on?
发生什么了？
It's the car. It lost power. It won't start.
发动机坏了 不能启动了
The car no start.
这车开不动了
What happened?
什么情况？
The engine failed.
引擎坏了
Ours, too.
我们的也是
What is it, Captain?
上尉 这是什么？
Defense positions.
防御阵型
Are we under attack?
有人攻击我们吗？
Defense positions.
防御阵型
Get around to the side.
恩乔 到那边去
Defense positions.
防御阵型
Hey. Defense positions!
嘿 防御阵型
No games.
不要耍花招
What do you see?
你们看到了什么？
Come in. Come in.
来了 来了
Over there! Look back!
- 那边  - 注意后方
Watch out!
当心
T'Challa, no!
特查拉 不要
This one's just a boy.
他还是个孩子
He got kidnapped as well.
他也是被拐骗了
Nakia...
娜奇雅
娜奇雅 特查拉前女友 虽然已经没有男女之间的关系了 但她还是作为黑豹
的一位挚友存在  帮黑豹排忧解难  也是所在部落的最强战士  擅长周旋的
超级间谍 解救弱势者的英雄
I...
我
- I wanted... - Hey!
- 我想..  - 嘿
I have her! Don't move! I will shoot!
- 她在我手里 - 不许动 否则我就开枪了
I will shoot her right now.
我会马上开枪的
You froze.
你还是愣住了
Ah...
啊
Why are you here? You've ruined my mission.
你为什么来这？你坏了我的任务
My father is dead, Nakia.
我父亲去世了 娜奇雅
I will be crowned king tomorrow.
明天我将加冕为王
And I wish for you to be there.
我希望你明天能到场
Carry yourselves home now.
你们自己回家吧
Thank you.
谢谢你
And take the boy. Get him to his people.
带上这个男孩 把他送回他的族人身边
Thank you oh.
谢谢你
You will speak nothing of this day.
今天的事你们不许对任何人说
Yes.
好
Thank you.
谢谢
Sister Nakia...
娜奇雅姐姐
My Prince...
王子殿下
we are home.
我们到家了
瓦 坎 达
This never gets old.
看多少次都不会腻
Queen Mother...
母后
Princess...
公主
苏睿公主  特查拉同父异母的妹妹 最爱的地方是她自己的实验室为瓦坎达
的黑科技做出很多贡献 不仅更新了黑豹的战衣  使其具有吸收并释放动能
的功能  还给自己制作了两个黑豹式能量手炮
My comfort for your loss.
请您节哀顺变
Thank you, Nakia.
谢谢你 娜奇雅
It is so good to have you back with us.
你能回来真是太好了
Take her to the River Province
带她去河畔
to prepare her for the ceremony.
为典礼做准备
Yes, General.
是 将军
Did he freeze?
他是不是愣住了？
Like an antelope in headlights.
像被车灯吓住的羚羊一样
Are you finished?
你说完了吗？
So surprised my little sister came
没想到我妹妹在大典日子前
to see me off before our big day.
亲自来接我
You wish!
你想得美
I'm here for the EMP beads. I've developed an update.
我是为了脉冲珠来的 我要给珠子做个升级
Update? No. It worked perfectly.
升级？不了吧 珠子挺好使的
How many times do I have to teach you?
你还要我教你多少次？
Just because something works
不能因为一件工具目前能正常使用
doesn't mean that it cannot be improved.
就觉得它不需要得到改进
You are teaching me? What do you know?
你在教我？你知道什么？
More than you.
知道的比你多
I can't wait to see what kind of update you make...
我倒要看看你的仪式礼服
to your ceremonial outfit.
能升级成什么样
Shuri!
舒莉
Sorry, Mother!
对不起 妈妈
How are you feeling today, Mama?
今天你感觉如何？妈妈
Proud.
骄傲
Your father and I would talk about this day all the time.
我和你父亲将永远记得这一天
He is with us...
他与我们同在...
and it is your time to be king.
现在该你继位称王了
伦 敦
英    国
大英博物馆
Good morning.
早上好
How can I help you?
需要帮助吗？
I was just checking out these artifacts.
哦 就随便看看这些工艺品
They tell me you're the expert.
他们告诉我你是这方面的专家
Ah. You could say that.
你可以这么说
They're beautiful.
它们很漂亮
埃里克 出生在瓦坎达某部落 原名尼•贾达卡 本是瓦坎达土著 从小离开瓦坎达生活
在纽约  后改名为埃里克•科尔芒戈  MIT研究生毕业  加入SEAL  JSOC 获得称号
“杀人魔” 其家族与黑豹家族之间有着非常深的仇恨 而且一心想要推翻黑豹统治
Where's this one from?
这是从哪儿来的？
The Bobo Ashanti tribe...
波波阿善提部落
present day Ghana...
也就是现在的加纳
19th century.
十九世纪的产物
For real?
真的吗？
What about this one?
那么这个呢？
That one's from the Edo people of Benin...
这个来自贝宁的埃多族
16th century.
十六世纪的
Now, tell me about this one.
那你再和我说说这个
Also from Benin, seventh century.
也是来自贝宁 七世纪的产物
Fula tribe, I believe.
我想 应该是富拉部落
Nah.
不对
I beg your pardon?
你说什么？
It was taken by British soldiers in Benin
表面上看来 它是被英国士兵从贝宁掠走的
but it's from Wakanda.
其实它来自瓦坎达
And it's made out of vibranium.
它是用振金制成的
Don't trip.
不用多说了
I'mma take it off your hands for you.
这个东西我从你这收了
These items aren't for sale.
这些东西是不出售的
How do you think your ancestors got these?
你认为你的祖先是怎么得到这些东西的呢？
You think they paid a fair price?
你觉得他们是用合理的价钱买下来的？
Or did they take it, like they took everything else?
还是直接夺走了它 就像他们夺走其它所有东西那样？
Sir, I'm going to have to
先生 我必须...
ask you to leave.
请你离开这里了
You got all this security in here
从我一进来
watching me ever since I walked in.
你就已经让所有安保人员盯着我了
But you ain't checking for
但你忘了检查
what you put in your body.
你自己吃进肚子里的东西
All right, mate. Let's have it.
好了 伙计 走吧
Come on, mate. Time.
快点 伙计 别磨蹭了
I think she might not be feeling too good.
我觉得她好像不大对劲
Somebody get some help! Come here!
嘿 快找人帮忙 这里
Call a doctor, please! Please, somebody, come help!
快叫医生 嘿 谁快来帮忙一下
Medical emergency right away
这里需要紧急救护
in the West African Exhibit, please, right away.
西非展区 请马上过来
Look out.
当心
Step back, please. Step back. Thank you.
大家请后退 配合一下 谢谢
Coming through over there. Medics coming through.
医生来了 医生来了
I'm gonna take a break.
我去休息一下
Let's give the lady some space, please.
请为这位女士让让路
Step back, please, gents.
请退后 先生们
Step back, please.
请退后
Hey, come here.
嘿 过来
Come here. It's okay.
过来 过来 别害怕
You can go, but just don't tell anyone, all right?
你可以走了 但不要告诉任何人 好吗？
Bro, why you ain't just shoot him right here?
老兄 你为什么不直接在这里开枪呢？
Because it's better to leave
因为犯罪现场
the crime scene more spread out.
越分散越好
Makes us look like amateurs.
让这案子看起来像是外行人做的
Now then, let's see if you know
那现在呢 我们来看看
what you're talking about.
你是不是真的懂行
That's just a taste.
这只是开胃菜
You're gonna be a rich boy.
你发财了 小子
You better sell that quick.
那你最好把它快点卖掉
It's already sold!
已经卖出去了
Whatever you try,
不管你有什么意图
the Wakandans'll probably show up.
瓦坎达人可能会出现
That'll make my day.
那今天我可要爽了
I can kill two birds with one stone.
我可以一石二鸟
You're not telling me that's vibranium, too?
你不是想跟我说那也是振金吧？
Nah, I'm just feeling it.
不是 我只是在感受这个面具
Onward!
前进
I, Zuri...
我 祖瑞
son of Badu...
巴杜之子..
give to you...
向各位介绍
Prince T'Challa...
特查拉王子
the Black Panther!
黑豹
The prince...
王子殿下
will now have the strength of the Black Panther...
现将黑豹之力
stripped away.
移除
Praise the ancestors.
愿祖上荣光永存
Victory in ritual combat...
在仪式战斗中
comes by yield or death.
胜利来自另一方的投降或者死亡
If any tribe wishes to put forth a warrior...
如果哪个部落有意派出勇士出战
I now offer...
那我现在就向他指明
a path to the throne.
通向王位之路
The Merchant Tribe will not challenge today.
商人部落今天不参加王位挑战
The Border Tribe will not challenge today.
边疆部落今天不参加王位挑战
The River Tribe will not challenge today.
河流部落今天不参加王位挑战
The Mining Tribe will not challenge today.
山矿部落今天不参加王位挑战
Is there any member of a royal blood...
还有哪位具有皇族血统的人
who wishes to challenge for the throne?
想参加王位挑战的吗？
This corset is really uncomfortable...
这个紧身内衣实在是太不舒服了
so could we all just wrap it up and go home?
既然没人挑战 我们还是收拾收拾各回各家好吧？
Mother!
妈妈
- Are they Jabari? - Yes.
- 他们是贾巴里部落的？- 是的
M'Baku, what are you doing here?
姆巴库 你来这干什么？
It's challenge day.
今天是王位挑战日
We have watched...
我们从深山里观察你们
and listened from the mountains!
聆听你们
We have watched with disgust...
看看你们这样子 我们感到厌恶
as your technological advancements
因为你们居然让一个小毛孩子
have been overseen by a child!
来监管你们那些先进科技
Who scoffs at tradition!
她蔑视传统
And now you want to hand the nation
现在你们还要把王位
over to this prince...
交给这个连父王
who could not keep his own father safe.
都保护不了的王子手上
Mmm?
不是吗？
We will not have it.
我们可不接受
I said, we will not have it, oh!
我说 我们不接受
I, M'Baku...
我 姆巴库...
leader of the Jabari...
贾巴里部落的领袖
I accept your challenge, M'Baku.
我接受你的挑战 姆巴库
Glory to Hanuman.
愿哈姆曼的荣光永存
Jabari!
贾巴里人就位
Dora Milaje!
多拉米拉吉护卫队
Onward!
前进
Let the challenge begin!
王位挑战开始
Oh!
哦
Stand up!
站起来
Come!
来啊
T'Challa!
特查拉
Where is your god now?
现在你的神在哪?
Yes!
是的
No powers.
没力气
No claws.
没爪子
No special suit, oh!
没有特制战服
Just a boy not fit to lead!
就是一个普通人 不适合领导我们
Show him who you are!
给他看你是谁
I am Prince T'Challa...
我是特查拉王子
son of King T'Chaka!
特查拉国王的儿子
You can do this, T'Challa!
你可以做到的 特查拉
Yes!
打的好
Come on!
加油
Yield! Don't make me kill you.
投降吧 别逼我杀你
I would rather die!
我宁愿死
T'Challa!
特查拉
You have fought with honor!
你已带着荣誉而战
Now yield! Your people need you.
现在投降吧 你的子民需要你
T'Challa!
特查拉
Yield, man!
投降 兄弟
T'Challa!
特查拉
Yes! Yes!
好的
I now present to you...
现在我向各位宣布
King T'Challa...
特查拉成功继承王位
the Black Panther.
黑豹
Zuri.
祖瑞
My King.
国王陛下
Wakanda forever!
瓦坎达万岁
Allow the Heart-Shaped Herb...
让这个心形草
to restore the powers of the Black Panther...
恢复黑豹的力量
and take you to the Ancestral Plane.
带你前往先祖的世界
T'Chaka...
特查卡
we call on you.
我们向您发起召唤
Come here to your son.
来这见您的儿子
Praise the ancestors.
愿祖上荣光永存
Father.
父亲
My son.
我的儿子
I'm sorry.
对不起
Stand up.
站起来
You are a king.
你是一个国王
What is wrong my son?
怎么了？儿子
I am not ready.
我还没准备好
Have you not prepared
你这一生不是
to be king your whole life?
都在为当上国王做准备吗?
Have you not trained and studied,
你不是一直在我身边
been by my side?
训练 学习吗？
That is not what I am talking about.
我指的不是这个
I am not ready to be without you.
我还是接受不了没有你的日子
A man who has not prepared his children
一个男人如果没有让
for his own death...
他的儿子坦然面对父亲的离世
has failed as a father.
那他就是一位失败的父亲
Have I ever failed you?
我有让你失望过吗？
Never.
从来没有
Tell me how to best protect Wakanda.
请告诉我如何才能守护好瓦坎达
I want to be a great king, Baba.
我希望成为一个伟大的国王 爸爸
Just like you.
就像你一样
You're going to struggle.
你会面临很多困难
So you'll need to surround yourself
所以你要任用
with people you trust.
自己信任的人
You're a good man with a good heart.
你是一个好男人 同时也有着一颗善良的心
And it's hard for a good man to be king.
对于一个好人来说 当国王很艰难
Breathe.
呼吸
T'Challa, breathe.
特查拉 呼吸
Breathe.
呼吸
He was there.
他在那
He was there. My father.
他就在那 我的父亲
Just one?
只要一个
Come home, Nakia.
回家吧 娜奇雅
I'm right here.
我就在家啊
Stay.
留下来
I came to support you and to honor your father...
我来是对你表示支持 和悼念你的父亲的
but I can't stay.
但我不能留下来
I found my calling out there.
外面的世界需要我
I've seen too many in need just to turn a blind eye.
我见过太多人对需要帮助的人视而不见
I can't be happy here...
我留在这是不会快乐的
knowing that there's people out there who have nothing.
因为我心里总会惦记着那些一无所有的人
What would you have Wakanda do about it?
你希望瓦坎达做什么呢？
Share what we have.
分享我们的科技
We could provide aid...
我们可以提供援助
and access to technology
和技术支持
and refuge to those who need it.
为那些需要的人提供庇护
Other countries do it, we could do it better.
其他国家也在做 我们可以做的更棒
We are not like these other countries, Nakia.
我们与这些国家是不同的 娜奇雅
If the world found out what we truly are...
如果世界了解了我们的真相
what we possess...
知道我们所拥有的一切
we could lose our way of life.
我们将会失去原有的生活
Wakanda is strong enough to help others
瓦坎达足够强大 帮助其他人的同时
and protect ourselves at the same time.
也能够保护自己
If you were not so stubborn, you would make a great queen.
如果你不那么固执己见 会是一个伟大的皇后
I would make a great queen because I am so stubborn.
正因为固执 我才能成为一个伟大的皇后
- Ah! See, you admit it! - If that's what I wanted.
- 噢 你看你已经承认了 - 如...如果我想当的话
Is that him?
是他吗？
Glory to Bast, man. Is he still growing?
女神保佑 他还在长大吗
Of course.
当然
I see Nakia is back.
我看到娜奇雅回来了
瓦卡比 瓦坎达国防指挥官 军事部部长 负责指挥瓦坎达军队 虽然表面上
与其族人皆穿着布袍  甚至饲养犀牛 但在发生战争时 布袍上的振金装置
能形成防御屏障 犀牛也披上振金甲板在战场上驰骋
You guys going to work it out?
你们俩会复合吗？
T'Challa...
特查拉
what's wrong?
怎么了？
Nakia thinks we should be doing more.
娜奇雅认为我们应该做更多的事
More, like what?
比如说？
Foreign aid, refugee programs.
对外援助 难民项目
You let the refugees in...
如果你让难民涌入
they bring their problems with them.
他们的麻烦也会跟着进来
And then Wakanda is like everywhere else.
之后瓦坎达就会变得像其他地方一样
Now if you said you wanted me and my men...
如果现在你要我和我的将士们一起
to go out there and clean up the world,
走出国门 荡尽世间不平事
then I'll be all for it.
那我也必定全力以赴
But waging war on other countries
但是就这么向其他国家发动过战争
has never been our way.
不是我们的行事风格
You, too, huh?
你的也响了？
Bast! We're in trouble.
天呀 我们有麻烦了
My King.
国王陛下
My love.
我的爱人
You will never guess who just popped up on our radar.
你肯定猜不到我们在雷达里发现了谁
A misidentified Wakandan artifact...
一件瓦坎达王国手工艺品 曾被误认为是其他文明的手工制品
was stolen yesterday from a British museum.
昨天被人从一家英国博物馆盗走
We have learned Ulysses Klaue...
我们得知尤利西斯•克劳
plans to sell the vibranium to an American buyer...
计划把那件振金制品
in South Korea...
在韩国出售给一位美国买家
tomorrow night.
交易时间是明天晚上
Klaue has escaped our pursuits for almost 30 years.
近30年来 我们一直没能抓到克劳
Not capturing him is, perhaps, my father's greatest regret.
没有抓到他 或许是我父亲最大的遗憾
I wish to bring Klaue back here to stand trial.
我希望把克劳带回来接受审判
Wakanda does not need a warrior right now.
瓦坎达王国现在需要的不是一个战士
We need a king.
我们需要一个国王
My parents were killed when he attacked.
我的父母在他的袭击中丧生
Not a day goes by when I do not think
我每天都在想着
about what Klaue took from us.
克劳从我们这夺走的一切
From me.
他从我身上夺去的那些
It's too great an opportunity to pass.
这么好的机会 怎能错过
Take me with you.
把我带上
We'll take him down together, side by side.
我们并肩作战一起把他拿下
I need you here protecting the border.
我需要你在这保护边疆
Then I ask...
那我得问一句
you kill him where he stands...
你是当场杀了他呢
or you bring him back to us.
还是把他带回到我们这呢？
You have my word.
我向你保证
I will bring him back.
我会把带他回来
We will proceed with the mission.
我们就这么干
My King!
国王陛下
Stop it. Stop it.
别这样 别这样
I've already sent a car ahead to Busan for you.
我已经帮你往釜山提前送了一辆车过去
Who are you taking with you to Korea?
你要带谁和你一起去韩国？
Okoye.
奥克耶
And Nakia as well.
还有娜奇雅
You sure it's a good idea to take your ex on a mission?
你确定带前女友执行任务是个好主意？
Yes.
是的
We'll be fine.
我们会没事的
Besides, you'll be on call should we need backup.
而且你要随时待命 我们需要支援
Yes!
太棒了
I have great things to show you, Brother.
我给你看些好东西 哥哥
Here are your communication devices for Korea.
这是你到韩国用的通讯设备
Unlimited range,
无限范围
also equipped with audio surveillance system.
还装备有音频监控系统
Check these out.
看看这些
Remote access Kimoyo Beads.
远程控制的基莫由珠
Updated to interface directly with my sand table.
升级过的界面直接和我的沙盘相连
Ah.
啊
And what are these?
这些是什么？
The real question is what are those?
真正的问题应该是 你穿的是什么？！
Why do you have your toes out in my lab?
为什么你要在我的实验室里露出脚趾？
What, you don't like my royal sandals?
什么？你不喜欢我的皇家凉鞋？
I wanted to go old school for my first day.
我上任第一天想走复古路线
I bet the Elders loved that.
好吧 我估计长老们会喜欢你这装束的
Try them on.
穿上试试
Fully automated.
全自动的
Like the old American movie Baba used to watch.
就像爸爸常看的美国老电影
Mmm.
嗯
And I made them completely sound absorbent.
我研制的鞋具有完美吸音特性
Interesting.
有意思
Guess what I call them.
猜我怎么叫它们
Sneakers.
运动鞋
Because you...
因为你...
Never mind.
当我没说
If you're going to take on Klaue...
如果你想活捉克劳
you'll need the best the design group has to offer.
你就需要设计团队提供给你的最尖端装备
Exhibit A.
看这第一件战服
- My design. - Old tech.
- 这是我设计的 - 过时的技术
- Old? - Functional, but old.
- 很老吗？- 能凑合用 但还是太过时了
"Hey, people are shooting at me.
“嘿 有人向我开枪
"Wait, let me put on my helmet."
等一下 让我先戴上头盔”
Enough.
够了吧
Now, look at these.
现在 瞧瞧这些
Do you like that one?
你喜欢那件吗？
Tempting.
很吸引人
But the idea is to not be noticed.
但是金色太显眼 不够低调
This one.
我要这件
Now tell it to go on.
现在让战服展示完整形态
Ooh!
哇哦
The entire suit sits within the teeth of the necklace.
整个战服都集成在牙齿项链上
Strike it.
打它一下
- Anywhere? - Mmm-hmm.
- 打哪都行？- 是的
Not that hard, genius!
天哪 别这么用力
You told me to strike it. You didn't say how hard.
你让我打的 你又没说用多大力度
I invite you to my lab,
我邀请你来我的实验室
and you just kick things around?
你却到处搞破坏吗？
Well, maybe you should make it a little stronger.
好吧 或许你该把它做的更牢固些
Hey.
嘿
Wait a minute.
等一下
The nanites absorb the kinetic energy...
战服内的纳米机器人会吸收动能
and hold it in place for redistribution.
动能会被储存于战服内 便于战服再次使用
Very nice.
很棒
Strike it again in the same spot.
你再打一下刚才的地方
You're recording?
你在录像？
For research purposes.
科研需要嘛
Delete that footage.
删除那段录像
釜 山
韩    国
This way.
这边
Bast willing, this will go quickly...
芭斯特女神的旨意 行动会很快结束
and I can get this ridiculous thing off my head.
然后我好摘掉这该死的假发
It looks nice. Just whip it back and forth.
挺好看的啊  你时不时前后甩甩头发
What? It's a disgrace.
什么？那太丢脸了
Hello Sophia.
你好 索菲亚
Good to see you.
很高兴见到你
Who are these two?
这两个人是谁？
My friends from Kenya. Very deep pockets. They're good.
是我肯尼亚那边的朋友 超级有钱的 人很不错
Good for trouble...
惹麻烦的本事也很不错吧...
...like you?
就跟你一样
Thank you!
谢谢
Spread out.
分开行动
The buyer is likely already here.
买家可能已经到这了
The woman outside.
刚刚外面的女人
What trouble was she referring to?
她说的“麻烦”指的是什么？
Ah... I got into a disagreement
我曾与某些象牙商
with some ivory traders.
干了一架
- Made a bit of a mess. - Hmm.
- 惹了点小麻烦 - 这样啊
And will there be any trouble tonight,
那么今晚会有麻烦吗？
Ms. Kenyan Heiress?
富有的肯尼亚继承人小姐
Depends...
这取决于...
on how quickly we finish the mission.
我们完成任务的速度
Can we please focus?
你们俩专注点好不好？
Thank you.
谢谢
Over here.
这边
One whiskey, please.
来一杯威士忌
Eyes up. Americans.
注意 有美国人
I count three.
我发现三个
Five.
是五个
How could you miss Greased Lightning
你怎么能无视你身后
there behind you?
的美国佬呢？
Six.
六个
Just spotted an old friend who works for the CIA.
我刚刚发现了一个就职于中央情报局的老朋友
It just got a little more complicated.
事情变得有点复杂了
罗斯探员 美国政府官员 CIA的特工领导人  瓦坎达问题专家 但他到了瓦
坎达就完全失去了领导权 一开始也有点不适应 特别是各种文化和先进的
黑科技让他大开眼界 他决定协助黑豹与他的家族一起保卫瓦坎达。
Agent Ross.
罗斯探员
Your Highness.
国王陛下
You are buying from Klaue.
你要和克劳做交易？
What I'm doing or not doing...
我是代表美国政府
on behalf of the U.S. government
做什么不做什么
is none of your concern.
不用你操心
Now, whatever the hell you're up to...
不管你要做什么...
do me a favor, stay out of my way.
算帮我个忙 别来碍我的事
I gave you Zemo.
是我把泽莫交给你的
Didn't I keep it under wraps...
我不是也对你的秘密一直保持沉默吗？
that the king of a third world country
你说的是你一个第三世界国家的国王
runs around in a bulletproof cat suit?
穿着防弹豹服在外面跑来跑去这个秘密 对吧？
I'd say we were even.
其实我们彼此彼此
You really need to leave, now.
你现在就应该离开这
Klaue is leaving out that door with me.
我会把克劳一起带走的
You've been warned.
我可警告你了
Three, craps.
骰子是三点
Hey, you won!
嘿 你赢了
You know what?
你知道吗？
I think I'll just take these...
我觉得我应该接手
bring them over here
把它们拿到我这边来
- and hold on for safekeeping. - Mmm-hmm.
- 代为保管 - 嗯
Okay, heads up. The king of Wakanda is here.
好了 注意点 瓦坎达国王在这里
He cannot leave with Klaue.
不能让他带走克劳
All right.
好吧
Vibranium from the attack on Sokovia
关于索科维亚事件中的振金
links back to a person...
线索都指向了一个人
that I'm not actually saying
虽然我不会明着承认
I'm here to make a deal with...
可我是来跟这个人做交易的
but that deal will not be called off.
而这笔交易是必须进行的
When the dust settles,
所以当事情水落石出的时候
you and me can work something out.
你和我可以一起解决这件事
I'm not here to make a deal.
我可不是来这做交易的
Klaue, plus eight!
克劳 还带了八个人来
General.
将军那边呢
In position to secure our exit.
已就位 保证我们的撤退路线安全
And the vibranium?
振金呢？
I don't see it yet.
我还没有看到
I thought there were no weapons allowed in here.
我记得这里是不许带武器进来的吧
There's not supposed to be.
确实是这样
Somebody did not get the memo.
有些人不听话
Definitely armed.
绝对是带着家伙呢
Well, that is quite the entourage.
哼 你这些随从还挺像样的嘛
You got a mixtape coming out?
你这阵容是要出混音唱片吗？
Oh, yeah. Yeah, actually, there is one.
对 没错 实话说我还真有一个
I'll send you the SoundCloud link, if you like.
如果你想要 我把云链接发给你
Hey, Dave, can you get the link to the tape?
嘿 戴夫 你把那个链接...？
Please, don't make me listen to your music.
拜托 我不想听你的什么音乐
I just meant you got a lot of people with you.
我的意思你带的人太多了
You think they're for you?
你以为他们是为你准备的？
Don't worry.
别担心
I can do a deal with you all by myself,
和你交易的只有我一个人
thank you very much.
非常感谢
Six more. It's a setup.
又来了六个人 这是个陷阱
You got the diamonds?
钻石你带来了吧？
Okay. That's enough.
我想这些够了吧
- We need to move on Klaue. - Stand down.
- 我们得对克劳动手了 - 等会儿别动
We can't afford a shootout.
要是来场枪战我们可吃不消
Vibranium?
振金呢？
易  碎
I was going to buy a fancy suitcase...
呃 我本打算买逼格高点的手提箱的 不过...
but I thought I'd save myself some money.
我还是想给我自己省点钱
It's now or never.
就现在 机不可失
Stand down!
别动
Hey!
嘿
I've been made.
我被识破了
Wakandans! They're here!
瓦坎达人 是他们
- Get outta here! - Kill 'em all!
- 快撤离此地  - 杀光他们
Diamonds, quick!
带上钻石 快走
Murderer!
杀人犯
You know, you look just like your old man.
你知道吗 你跟你老爸可真像
I made it rain!
钞票满天飞啊
Let's get out of here, boss!
我们撤吧 老板
That was awesome! That was awesome!
太壮观了 真刺激
Let's go! Go, go, go, come on!
我们走 快走 快点啊
- Do we just leave him? - He'll catch up.
- 我们不管他了？- 他会追上来的
Shuri!
舒莉
Yes!
太好了 到我登场了
Remote driving system activated.
远程驾驶系统已激活
Wait! Which side of the road is it?
等等 车在路的哪边？
For Bast's sake!
我的天啊
- Just drive! - Okay, calm down!
- 别管了 开就是了 - 好吧 冷静
Whoo! Let's go!
哇哦 出发喽
Put some music on. What do you think this is, a funeral?
来点音乐 这么安静干嘛 参加葬礼吗？
Which one is he in now?
他在哪辆车上？
Hey, split up!
嘿 分头走
- They're trying to lose us. - I'll take the right.
- 他们想甩掉我们 - 我追右边那辆
We'll take the other two! I see a shortcut.
我们负责另外两辆 我抄近道去追
We're not going to make it!
这我可过不去了
Keep going!
继续追
Whoo! Brother!
哦 哥你厉害
Hey, what was that?
嘿 那是什么鬼？
Don't worry about it. You're doing great.
别分心 你做的很好
Guns.
还开枪呢
So primitive!
攻击手段真原始
It's a vibranium car, you idiots!
那车是振金的 你这蠢货
The bullets won't penetrate!
子弹打不透
What are you doing?
你要干什么？
Just drive.
你开就是了
- Whoo! - Shit!
哦 见鬼
Hey, look at your suit.
嘿 注意你的战袍
You've been taking bullets,
你一直在挨枪子
charging it up with kinetic energy.
战袍会储存动能的
Pull around the truck.
超过那辆车
Where'd he go?
他去哪儿了？
You show-off.
你真秀啊
There he is!
追上他了
Hold tight!
抓紧
All right. Let's have some fun!
好吧 来点刺激的
Hop in.
上车
Put that spear in the trunk.
把矛放后备箱
Faster, Shuri.
加速 舒莉
I'm going as fast as I can!
我已经开到最快了
Take a right! Take a right!
右转 右转
No, no, no!
不 不 不 不 不
Brother!
哥哥
Klaue!
克劳
Did you think we would forget?
你觉得我们能忘的了吗？
Look at me, murderer!
看着我 杀人犯
Where did you get this weapon?
你从哪里来搞到这个武器的？
You savages didn't deserve it.
你们这种野蛮人不配拥有它
Oh, mercy, King. Mercy.
哦 手下留情 国王 手下留情
Every breath you take is mercy from me.
你的每一次呼吸都源自我的仁慈
King!
国王
The world watches.
全世界都看着呢
Come on. Guys. Let's go, huh?
来吧 几位 我们撤 好吧？
Yeah.
这就对了
Hello.
你好啊
I can see you! I can. I can see you.
我能看到你 我能..我能看到你哦
So this is a big mess, huh?
这动静闹得很大啊
I figured we could go good cop, bad cop.
我想我们可以一个唱红脸 一个唱白脸
I'll talk to him first, then you guys go in.
我先和他谈 然后你们上
We can't let him talk to Klaue alone.
我们不能让他单独和克劳谈
Better to let him talk to Klaue alone for 5 minutes than to make a scene here.
让他跟克劳谈五分钟 比在这里闹翻要好
After your questioning,
你审问完之后
we will take him back to Wakanda with us.
我们会把他带回瓦坎达
What? No. Look, I like you, a lot.
什么？不 听着 我很欣赏你
But he's in my custody now. He's not going anywhere.
但他现在是收押在我这 他哪也不能去
Listen, I'm doing you guys a favor
听着 要不是我帮你们
by letting you even be in here.
你们连这都进不来
If he touches you again,
如果他再碰你一次
I'm going to impale him to this desk.
我就把他钉到桌子上
Does she speak English?
她会说英语吗？
When she wants to.
她想说的时候才会说
I'm going in.
我进去了
When I'm done, you guys are up.
我结束之后 你们上
- Agent Ross. - Yeah?
- 特工罗斯  - 怎么了？
I do appreciate your help in Busan.
我很感谢你在釜山能帮我们
You see that?
你看见了吧
It's called diplomacy.
这就叫外交
You're welcome.
不客气
Okoye.
- 奥克耶 - 啊啊
Play nice.
客气点
Americans.
美国人就这德性
You know, you really shouldn't trust the Wakandans.
你真的不应该信瓦坎达人的话
I'm much more your speed.
咱俩才是一个步调上的人
I don't trust anybody, not in this job.
干我这行的 从不相信任何人
But what I am interested in is that arm cannon out there.
但我感兴趣的是那个手臂大炮
Where'd you get that?
你从哪儿拿到的？
It's an old mining tool that I made some adjustments to.
那是一个旧的采矿工具 我做了一些改装
But I can get you one, if you like.
但是我可以 送你一个 如果你喜欢的话
Why don't you give me the name of your supplier,
要不你告诉我你供应商的名字
and I'll ask them.
然后我去问他们如何？
He's right outside.
他就在外面
Why don't you ask him yourself?
你为什么不亲自问问他呢？
What? T'Challa?
什么？特查拉？
You're telling me that weapon on your arm is from Wakanda?
你是想跟我说你手臂上的武器来自瓦坎达？
Bingo.
对了
What do you actually know about Wakanda?
你究竟对瓦坎达王国了解多少？
Um...
呃
Shepherds, textiles, cool outfits.
牧羊人 纺织品 还有炫酷的衣服
It's all a front.
这都是表面的东西
Explorers searched for it for centuries.
探险家们找了几个世纪
El Dorado, the Golden City.
传说中的黄金之城
They thought they could find it in South America...
他们以为能在南美洲找到黄金之城
but it was in Africa the whole time.
但是其实 黄金之城一直在非洲
A technological marvel.
这是一个科技铸就的奇迹
All because it was built on a mound
它是以目前人类已知最珍贵的金属
of the most valuable metal known to man.
为基础建立起来的
Isipho, they call it. The gift.
他们叫它 天赐的礼物
Vibranium.
也就是振金
Vibranium, yeah, strongest metal on earth.
振金 地球上最坚硬的金属
It's not just a metal.
这不仅仅是一种金属
They sew it into their clothes.
他们还把它缝进衣服里
It powers their city, their tech...
振金为他们的城市供能 强化了他们的科技水平
their weapons.
帮助他们生产出更强的武器
Weapons?
武器？
Yeah.
是的
Makes my arm cannon look like a leaf blower.
我的手臂炮弹和他们的武器比起来跟玩具没什么两样
That's a nice fairy tale,
故事编的挺好
but Wakanda is a third world country...
但是瓦坎达是第三世界的国家
and you stole all their vibranium.
而你偷了他们全部的振金
I stole...
我偷走了...？
All of it?
所有的？
I took a tiny piece of it.
我只拿了一点点
They have a mountain full of it.
他们那里的振金堆积如山
They've been mining it for thousands of years...
他们已经挖掘了几千年
and they still haven't scratched the surface.
也不过是挖走了点皮毛而已
I'm the only outsider who's seen it
我是唯一一个见过那景象
and got out of there alive.
还能活着回来的外来者
If you don't believe me,
如果你不信我 你去问问你的朋友
you ask your friend what his suit is made of.
他那身衣服是用什么做的
What his claws are made of.
他那爪子是用什么做的
Your father told the UN...
你的父亲告诉联合国
that Klaue stole all the vibranium you had.
克劳偷走了你们所有的振金
But now he's telling me you have more.
可现在 他却说你们手上还有
And you believe the word
你相信一个被绑在椅子上的
of an arms dealer strapped to a chair?
军火商说的话吗
Where is that?
那是哪里
Back there.
后巷
How much more are you hiding?
你还隐瞒了什么
Something is happening out back.
后面情况不对
Get down!
趴下
Stand down!
Cover!
找掩护
Grenade!
手榴弹
I see you took your time, didn't you?
你们不是很从容的吗
My King!
我的国王
My King.
Nakia.
娜吉雅
He just jumped in front of me.
他跳出来 挡在了我前面
I don't think he'll make it here.
我觉得他要撑不住了
It hit his spine.
他的脊柱中枪了
Give me a Kimoyo Bead.
给我一颗基莫由珠
This will stabilize him for now.
这样应该能稳住一会儿
Give him to us.
让我们带他走
We can save him.
我们能救他
Our mission was to bring back Klaue.
我们的任务是带回克劳
We failed.
我们失败了
This man is a foreign intelligence operative.
这人可是外国情报人员
How do we justify bringing him into our borders?
我们怎么可以随便带他入境
He took a bullet for me.
他替我挨了枪
That was his choice.
那是他的选择
So now we are just supposed to let him die?
所以我们就应该见死不救吗
Let us consider that we heal him.
假如说我们救了他
It is his duty to report back to his country.
他的职责是向他的国家报告
And as king, it is your duty to protect ours.
而作为国王 你的责任是保护我们
I'm well aware of my duties, General.
我非常清楚我的职责 将军
I cannot just let him die...
但既然知道我们能救他
knowing we can save him.
我们就不能眼睁睁地看着他死
Where exactly are we taking him?
我们到底要带他去哪儿
Great! Another broken white boy for us to fix.
真棒 又来了一位需要治疗的白人了
This is going to be fun.
这事真有意思
He will live.
他会活下来的
W'Kabi is here.
瓦卡比来了
What's going on, brother? Where is Klaue?
怎么回事 兄弟 克劳人呢
He's not here.
他不在这儿
He slipped through our hands.
他从我们眼皮底下溜了
"Slipped"?
“溜了”？
For 30 years, your father was in power and did nothing.
你父亲掌权的三十年间 毫无作为
With you, I thought it'd be different.
我以为你掌权后会有所改变
But it's more of the same.
但似乎没什么两样
Let's get going, boss.
走吧 老大
You always sell to the CIA?
你一直把弄来的东西卖给中央情报局的人吗
I sell to the highest bidder.
价高者得
But don't you worry. When I get back to Joburg...
别担心 等我回到约翰内斯堡后
and I lay low for a bit,
我会低调一点
I'll make sure both you guys get paid.
我保证会付你们薪水的
Oh, I ain't worried about the money, bro.
我不担心钱 兄弟
I know you good for it.
我知道你付得起
On our way back, just drop us off in Wakanda.
回程时把我们送到瓦坎达就行
You don't want to go there, boy.
你不会想去那里的 孩子
Yeah, I do.
我已经想好了
Drop it!
放下枪
Or your little Bonnie and Clyde routine
不然你的小妮子
ends today.
就没命了
Put your gun down now!
立刻放下枪
I'm sorry.
对不起
- Sorry, Erik. - It's gonna be okay.
- 对不起 埃里克 - 会没事的
You really want to go to Wakanda?
你真的想回瓦坎达吗
They're savages.
他们都是野蛮人
This is what they do to people like us.
这是他们对我们这些人干的好事
I ain't worried about no brand.
我才不在意伤疤呢
Check these out.
给你瞧
Each one is for a kill.
每一个都是一条人命
You can scar yourself as much as you'd like.
你可以尽情给自己留下伤疤
To them, you'll just be an outsider.
对他们而言 你只是外来者
You're crazy to think that you can walk in there.
你想踏入那里 简直痴心妄想
Ah, to think I saw you as some crazy American.
我竟然以为你只是个美国疯子
Leave us!
都退下
So your mission did not go as planned.
所以你没能按计划完成任务
What happened to my uncle N'Jobu?
当年在我恩乔布叔叔身上发生了什么
My father told me he disappeared.
我父亲只是告诉我 他消失了
There was a man today...
但今天有个男人
wearing a ring identical to this one.
戴着和我手上这枚一样的戒指
That is not possible.
这不可能
He helped Klaue escape from us and he was wearing this ring!
他从我们手中带走了克劳 还戴着这枚戒指
My grandfather's ring!
我祖父的戒指！
Do not tell me what is possible.
别说什么不可能
Tell me the truth!
告诉我真相
Some truths...
有些真相
are too much to bear, T'Challa.
沉重得难以承受 特查拉
That is not your choice to make.
这由不得你来决定
What happened to him?
他怎么了？
I promised the king to say nothing.
我答应了国王保守秘密
I am your king now!
我才是你的王！
Your uncle took...
你叔叔当时在美国
a War Dog assignment in America.
执行一项间谍任务
Your father...
你父亲
placed me there...
把我安插在那
to observe...
暗中观察
unbeknownst to him.
你父亲不知道的是
Your uncle fell in love with an American woman.
你叔叔爱上了一个美国女人
They had a child.
他们还生了孩子
The hardships he saw there...
看到外面世界的苦难
radicalized your uncle.
让你的叔叔愈发激进
I observed for as long as I could.
我观察了很久
Their leaders have been assassinated.
他们的总统遭到暗杀
Communities flooded with drugs and weapons.
社区里充斥着毒品和武器
They are overly policed and incarcerated.
我们的黑人同胞受到压迫 被关进监狱
All over the planet...
同样的事情
our people suffer because
在世界各地都在上演
they don't have the tools to fight back.
因为他们没有武器去还击
With vibranium weapons,
有了振金武器
they could overthrow every country...
他们便能推翻所有国家
and Wakanda could rule them all
瓦坎达也能
the right way.
让这些国家走上正轨
He knew your father would not support this.
他知道你的父亲不会支持
So, your uncle betrayed us.
所以你叔叔背叛了我们
No!
不
He helped Klaue steal the vibranium.
他帮助克劳窃取振金
No, no, no.
不 不 不
You will return home at once...
我命令你即刻回国
where you will face the Council...
你将会面对议会的质询
and inform them of your crimes.
并向他们坦白你的罪行
He drew his weapon on me.
他拿武器对准我
No!
不要
Your father killed his own brother...
你父亲杀了他的亲兄弟
to save my life.
救了我一命
Speak nothing of this.
这件事不要再提起
And the child?
那个孩子呢？
We left him.
我们丢下了他
We had to...
我们必须
maintain...
去维持
the lie.
这个谎言
What is this?
这是什么？
Just a little gift.
只是个小礼物
Who are you?
你是什么人
All right, where am I?
好吧 这是哪儿？
Don't scare me like that, colonizer!
别这么吓我 殖民佬
What? My name is Everett.
殖什么？我是埃弗雷特
Yes, I know. Everett Ross...
我知道 埃弗雷特•罗斯
former air force pilot and now CIA.
前空军飞行员 现中央情报局探员
Right.
对
Okay, is this Wakanda?
这里是瓦坎达吗
No, it's Kansas.
这是堪萨斯
How long ago was Korea?
韩国的事是什么时候
Yesterday.
昨天
I don't think so.
我不信
Bullet wounds don't just magically heal overnight.
枪弹伤不会奇迹般地一夜痊愈
They do here.
这里可以
But not by magic, by technology.
但不是靠魔法 而是靠科技
Don't touch anything. My brother will return soon.
别乱碰东西 我哥哥马上就回来
These train things...
那些火车
that's magnetic levitation, right?
是磁悬浮列车 对吧
Obviously.
明显是
Obviously, but I've never seen it this efficient.
明显是 但我没见过这么...高级的
The light panels, what are they?
那些发光板是做什么用的？
- Sonic stabilizers. - Sonic what?
- 音速稳定器 - 音速啥？
In its raw form...
直接高速运输
vibranium is too dangerous
原始形态的振金
to be transported at that speed...
过于危险
so I developed a way to temporarily deactivate it.
所以我设计出了一种方法 暂时钝化它
There's vibranium on those trains?
那些列车上装着振金？
There's vibranium all around us.
这里到处都有振金
That's how I healed you.
你的伤也是它治好的
Where is T'Challa?
特查拉在哪
His Kimoyo Beads have been switched off.
他把他的基莫由珠关掉了
Well, we are not joined at the hip, Okoye.
我们不要当跟屁虫吧 奥克耶
A man showed up at the border
在边境出现了一个男人
who claims to have killed Klaue.
声称自己杀了克劳
What?
你说什么
W'Kabi is transporting him, as we speak, to the palace.
现在瓦卡比正带着他前往宫殿
We need to find your brother!
我们要找到你的哥哥
An outsider?
一个外来者
No, a Wakandan.
不 是瓦坎达人
He's not a Wakandan.
他才不是瓦坎达人
He's one of ours.
他跟我一样是美国人
He killed his own brother...
他杀了他的亲兄弟
and left a child behind...
然后还抛下了一个孩子
with nothing.
孤身一人
What kind of king...
什么样的国王...
What kind of man does that?
什么样的人才会做出这样的事？
No man is perfect.
人无完人
Not even your father.
你父亲也一样
He didn't even give him a proper burial.
他甚至都没有好好安葬他
My uncle N'Jobu betrayed us, but my father...
我的叔叔恩乔布背叛了我们 但是我的父亲...
he may have created something even worse.
他犯下的过错可能更为深重
Hey.
嘿
Look at me.
看着我
You can't let your father's mistakes define who you are.
你不能用你父亲的罪过来定义你自己
You get to decide what kind of king you are going to be.
你要当一个怎样的国王得由你自己决定
Brother, you need to get here now!
哥哥 你得马上过来
Erik Stevens.
埃里克•史蒂文斯
Graduated Annapolis age 19...
19岁就从安纳波利斯大学毕业
MIT for grad school.
然后拿到了麻省理工的研究生学位
Joined the SEALs and went straight to Afghanistan...
加入海豹突击队后被派往了阿富汗
where he wrapped up confirmed kills,
他在那儿杀人
like it was a video game.
跟打游戏似的
Started calling him Killmonger.
人们开始叫他 克尔芒戈
He joined a JSOC ghost unit. Now these guys are serious.
他还加入了美国联合特种作战司令部的幽灵部队 这些家伙可不是闹着玩的
They will drop off the grid...
他们能秘密潜伏
so they can commit assassinations
去执行暗杀
and take down governments.
甚至推翻政府
Did he reveal anything about his identity?
他有暴露过他的身份信息吗？
He has a War Dog tattoo...
他身上有间谍的纹身
but we have no record of him.
但是我们资料库里没有他的信息
Is this man Wakandan or not?
这个人到底是不是瓦坎达人
Tell us what is going on.
告诉我们这是怎么回事
Speak.
说话
I'm standing in your house...
我现在站在你们的王宫里 告诉你们
serving justice to a man
我为你们制裁了一个偷了你们振金
who stole your vibranium and murdered your people.
又谋害了你们人民的人
Justice your king couldn't deliver.
你们的国王都没能制裁他
I don't care that you brought Klaue.
我才不在乎你有没有把克劳带回来
Only reason I don't kill you where you stand
我到现在还没有杀你是因为
is because I know who you are.
我知道你是谁
Now, what do you want?
现在 你想要什么
I want the throne.
我想要那王位
My goodness.
口气真大
Y'all sittin' up here comfortable.
你们都坐在这舒舒服服的
Must feel good.
感觉很好吧
It's about two billion people
但全球还有二十亿
all over the world that looks like us.
和我们肤色一样的同胞
But their lives are a lot harder.
还活在水深火热之中
Wakanda has the tools to liberate 'em all.
瓦坎达有着能解放他们的工具
And what tools are those?
那是什么工具呢？
Vibranium. Your weapons.
振金 你们的武器
Our weapons will not be used to wage war on the world.
我们的武器不是用来向世界发起战争的
It is not our way to be judge, jury and executioner...
我们不会拿着振金去当世界警察 去判决 审查
for people who are not our own.
甚至处决 别国的子民的
Not your own?
别国的子民？
But didn't life start right here on this continent?
但生命不就是从这块大陆上起源的吗？
So ain't all people your people?
全人类不都是你的子民吗？
I am not king of all people. I am king of Wakanda.
我不是全人类的国王 我是瓦坎达的国王
And it is my responsibility
而这也是我的责任
to make sure our people are safe...
保证所有瓦坎达人的安危
and that vibranium does not fall
以及确保振金...
into the hands of a person like you.
不会落入像你这种人的手里
- Mmm... - Son.
儿子
We have entertained this charlatan for too long.
我们陪这个冒牌货玩得够久了
Reject his request.
不要答应他的要求
Oh, I ain't requesting nothing.
我还没提出要求呢
- Ask who I am. - You're Erik Stevens.
- 问问我是谁 - 你是埃里克•史蒂文斯
An American black operative.
美国黑人间谍
A mercenary nicknamed Killmonger.
人称克尔芒戈的佣兵
That's who you are.
这就是你的真实身份
That's not my name, Princess.
这可不是我的名字 公主
Ask me, King.
问我啊 国王
No.
不
Ask me.
快问我
Take him away.
把他带下去
Who are you?
你到底是谁？
I am N'Jadaka, son of Prince N'Jobu.
我是恩贾达卡 恩乔布王子之子
Son of N'Jobu?
恩乔布之子
I found my daddy
我父亲死的时候
with Panther claws in his chest!
胸前可是有豹子爪印
You ain't the son of a king. You a son of a murderer.
你不是什么国王的儿子 你就是一个凶手的儿子
You're lying!
你撒谎
- Lies! - I'm afraid not, Queen Mother.
- 一派胡言！ - 恐怕他说的是真的 母后
What?
什么
The descendent of N'Jobu.
恩乔布的后代
Hey, Auntie.
你好啊 伯母
I'm exercising my blood right
我现在行使我作为王族后裔的权利
to challenge for the mantles of king...
向王位发出挑战
and Black Panther.
挑战黑豹
Do not do this, T'Challa.
别接受他的挑战 特查拉
As the son of Prince N'Jobu,
身为恩乔布王子的后裔
he is within his rights.
他有这个权利
He has no rights here!
他在这里没有任何权利
The challenge will take weeks to prepare.
挑战要做数周的准备工作
Weeks? I don't need weeks.
数周？我不需要这么久
The whole country ain't gotta be there. I just need him.
我不需要整个国家在场 我只需要他
And somebody to get me outta these chains.
以及一个可以帮我松绑的人
T'Challa, what do you know of this?
特查拉 你想清楚了吗？
I accept your challenge.
我接受你的挑战
He'll never beat T'Challa.
他不可能打败特查拉的
He should've just come to the first challenge
他就应该在上次挑战的时候来
and gotten it over with.
一次性搞定
The king will now have the strength
国王现将
of the Black Panther stripped away.
黑豹之力移除
Where is Agent Ross?
罗斯探员在哪
I locked him in the office. He's not going anywhere.
我把他关在办公室了 他跑不了的
This is your last chance.
这是你最后的机会
Throw down your weapons,
放下武器
and we can handle this another way.
这样我们还有商量的余地
I lived my entire life waitin' for this moment.
我的一生都在为这一时刻做准备
I trained, I lied, I killed...
我艰苦训练 谎话连天 杀人无数
just to get here.
就是为了到这里
I killed in America, Afghanistan...
我征战过美国 阿富汗
Iraq.
伊拉克
I took life from my own brothers and sisters
我剥夺生命
right here on this continent.
剥夺来自这片陆地的兄弟姐妹们的生命
And all this death...
杀了这么多人
just so I could kill you.
就只是为了杀你
Let the challenge begin.
挑战现在开始
Yield!
投降！
Snap out of it, T'Challa!
干掉他 特查拉！
Come on, get up.
快啊 站起来
Come here.
来啊
This is for my father.
这是为了我的父亲
Erik!
埃里克！
- Zuri, no. - Stop!
- 祖瑞 不 - 住手
- Zuri! - Zuri, don't!
- 祖瑞 - 祖瑞 不
I am the cause of your father's death.
是我让你的父亲丧命
Not him.
不是他
Take me.
杀我
I'll take you both, Uncle James.
你们俩都要死 詹姆斯叔叔
No!
不！
No! No!
不！ 不！
Zuri, no!
祖瑞 不
No!
不！
No! No! Zuri! Zuri!
不 不！祖瑞！ 祖瑞！
No! No!
不！ 不！
Is this your king? Huh?
这就是你们的国王？
Is this your king?
The Black Panther,
黑豹
who's supposed to lead you into the future?
本应是带领你们走向未来的人
Come on, Brother!
加油 哥哥！
Is there nothing that can be done?
真的没有办法了吗？
Him?
就他？
He's supposed to protect you?
还想保护你们？
- No. - No!
- 不要 - 不要
No!
不！
Nah. I'm your king.
不 我才是你们的王
- No! No! - We have to go now!
- 不！ - 我们得马上离开
Queen Mother, let's go!
母后 我们走！
The Queen Mother and Shuri, they are safe?
太后和舒莉 她们安全吗？
Yes.
安全
Thank you.
谢谢你
We should get to them immediately.
我们得马上去找她们
I cannot
我不能
What?
什么？
Though my heart is with you.
去吧 我的心和你在一起
We cannot turn over our nation to a man
我们不能把我们的国家
who showed up here only hours ago.
交给一个才出现了几个小时的人
He is of royal blood.
他有皇室血统
- He killed T'Challa! - In ritual combat.
- 他杀了特查拉！ - 那是在格斗仪式中
Does that really matter?
那还不是一样？
You are the greatest warrior Wakanda has.
你是瓦坎达最出色的战士
Help me overthrow him before he becomes too strong.
帮我在他强大起来之前推翻他
Overthrow?
推翻？
Nakia!
娜奇雅
I'm not a spy who can come and go as they so choose!
我不是那种来去随意的间谍
I am loyal to that throne, no matter who sits upon it.
我所效忠的是那个王座 不管是谁坐在上面
What are you loyal to?
你效忠的是什么？
I loved him.
我爱他
I loved my country, too.
我也爱我的国家
Then you serve your country.
那你就应该效忠你的国家
No. I save my country.
不 我要拯救我的国家
What's wrong?
出什么事了
The king is dead.
国王死了
Come with me, unless you want to join him.
你要不想跟他为伍就跟我走
First Baba.
先是爸爸
And now my brother.
现在轮到我的哥哥
Mama, we didn't even get to bury him.
妈妈 我们甚至都没能安葬他
- It's me. - Nakia. Who is this man?
- 是我 - 娜奇雅 这人是谁？
He's a friend of T'Challa's. He saved my life.
他是特查拉的朋友 他救过我的命
Where's Okoye?
奥克耶呢？
Okoye is not coming.
奥克耶没有来
She and the Dora Milaje will serve the new king.
她和多拉米拉吉护卫队会效忠新王
Wait here.
在这等我
What has happened to our Wakanda?
我们的瓦坎达怎么了
Allow the Heart-Shaped Herb...
让心形草
to give you the powers of the Black Panther...
赋予你黑豹的力量
and take you to the Ancestral Plane.
带你前往先祖的世界
What did I tell you about going into my things?
我怎么跟你说的 别翻我的东西
What did you find?
你找到了什么
Your home.
你的家
I gave you a key hoping that you might see it someday.
我给你钥匙 就是希望你有一天能看到它
Yes. The sunsets there
没错 那里的日落
are the most beautiful in the world.
是全世界最美的
But I fear you still may not be welcome.
但我担心你不会受欢迎
Why?
为什么？
They will say you are lost.
他们会说你走丢了
But I'm right here.
但我就在这里啊
No tears for me?
不为我流泪吗
Everybody dies.
每个人都难逃一死
It's just life around here.
这里的生活就是这样
Well, look at what I have done.
瞧瞧我都做了些什么
I should've taken you back long ago.
我早就该带你回去的
Instead, we are both abandoned here.
而现在 我们都被抛弃在这儿了
Well, maybe your home is the one that's lost.
也许走丢了的是你的家才对
That's why they can't find us.
所以他们才找不到我们
Breathe! Breathe, My King, breathe.
呼吸 呼吸 陛下 呼吸
Breathe. Breathe. Breathe.
呼吸 呼吸
The Heart-Shaped Herb did that?
是心形草的作用吗
This all of it?
全部的都在这么
Yes. So when it comes time for another king,
当下一任国王继位时
we will be ready.
我们就能准备好
Another king?
下一任国王？
Yeah, go ahead and burn all that.
去把那些都烧了
My King, we cannot do that. It is our tradition...
陛下 我们不能这么做 这是我们的传统
When I tell you to do something, I mean that shit.
我让你做什么 你就得做什么
Burn it all!
全烧了
You know, where I'm from...
你们知道么 在我的家乡
when black folks started revolutions,
黑人闹革命的时候
they never had the firepower...
他们没有武器
or the resources to fight their oppressors.
也没有资源去反抗压迫者
Where was Wakanda?
那时瓦坎达在哪里呢？
Yeah, all that ends today.
这种局面以后将不复存在
We got spies embedded in every nation on Earth.
我们在地球上每个国家里都安插有间谍
Already in place.
全都已经就位
I know how colonizers think.
我知道殖民者是怎么想的
So we're gonna use their own strategy against 'em.
所以我们要以其人之道还治其人之身
We're gonna send vibranium weapons out to our War Dogs.
我们会把振金武器送到我们的间谍手中
They'll arm oppressed people all over the world...
他们会武装全世界被压迫的人民
so they can finally rise up and kill those in power.
这样他们才能站起来反抗 杀掉掌权者
And their children.
和他们的孩子
And anyone else who takes their side.
以及所有他们的同伙
It's time they know the truth about us!
是时候向他们展示我们真正的实力了
We're warriors!
我们是战士
The world's gonna start over, and this time, we're on top.
世界秩序将被重新建立 而这一次 将由我们来掌权
The sun will never set on the Wakandan empire.
瓦坎达将成为日不落帝国
Wakanda has survived for so long...
瓦坎达之所以能在世界中存在这么久
by fighting when only absolutely necessary.
正是因为我们只在绝对必要的时候才打仗
Wakanda survived in the past this way, yes.
瓦坎达过去是这样的 没错
But the world is changing, General.
但世界在改变啊 将军
Elders, it is getting smaller.
长老们 瓦坎达的优势受到挑战
The outside world is catching up...
外面的世界正在迎头赶上
and soon it will be the conquerors
不久之后 它要么征服别人
or the conquered.
要么就被别人征服
I'd rather be the former.
我宁愿做征服者
You heard your orders. Let's get to it.
你们听到命令了 开始行动吧
So where are we going again?
我们要去哪来着
We're taking the Heart-Shaped Herb
我们要把心形草
to Jabariland.
带到贾巴里的领地
Heart-Shaped Herb? What is that?
心形草？那是什么？
It gives whoever takes it heightened abilities.
它会增强服用者的能力
It's what made T'Challa so strong.
正是它让特查拉变得那么强大的
Nakia.
娜奇雅
I don't like this.
我不喜欢这样
The Herb belongs to us.
心形草是属于我们的
We may be creating a bigger monster with M'Baku.
我们这样可能会让姆巴库成为更为可怕的恶魔
Nakia, you should take it yourself.
娜奇雅 你应该给自己用
I am a spy with no army.
我只是个间谍 手上没有军队
I wouldn't stand a chance.
我一点机会都没有的
We'll go.
我们走吧
Oh, boy.
天哪
Oh, shit.
该死
Look down. Stay calm.
低头 冷静
Shuri.
舒莉
Look down.
低头
My son...
我的儿子
was murdered in ritual combat.
在格斗仪式中被谋杀了
- Were the odds fair? - Yes, but...
- 格斗的过程公平吗 - 公平 但
So it was less a murder than a defeat.
那就不是谋杀 而是战败
- Do not rub our noses in it! - Silence!
- 这轮不到你来说！- 安静
I make the pronouncements here, girl.
这里我说了算 小姑娘
Look, uh, Your Highness, the new king is a U.S...
听我说 陛下 新王是一个...
The new king...
新王...
You cannot talk!
你不准说话
One more word,
再多说一个字
and I will feed you to my children.
我就把你喂给我的孩子们
I'm kidding. We are vegetarians.
开玩笑的 我们是素食主义者
Great Gorilla M'Baku...
伟大的人猿姆巴库
this is why we are here.
这就是我们来这儿的原因
To offer this to you.
把这个献给你
An outsider sits on our throne.
一个外来者坐在了我们的王位上
Only you can help us stop him.
只有你能帮我们阻止他
Come with me.
跟我来
Impossible!
这不可能
Is he breathing?
他还活着吗
He's in a coma. Barely clinging to life.
他昏迷了 只剩一口气
One of our fishermen found him
我们的一个渔夫
at the edge of the river border.
在河边发现了他
He brought him to me.
并把他带到了我这里
Why do you have him in the snow?
为什么把他埋在雪里？
It is the only thing keeping him
这是唯一
from joining the ancestors.
能挽回他性命的办法
We need to get him to my lab. I can heal him there.
我们得把他带回实验室 在那我就可以救活他
Take him. He'll be dead in seconds.
带他走吧 他撑不了多久的
Nakia, the Herb.
娜奇雅 草药
I call upon the ancestors.
列祖列宗在上
I call upon Bast.
芭丝特女神在上
I am here with my son, T'Challa.
吾与吾子 特查拉
Heal him.
拯救他
We must bury him. Cover him. Cover him!
我们必须把他埋起来 盖住他 盖住他
Okay.
好的
Praise the ancestors.
愿祖上荣光永存
Wake up, T'Challa.
醒来吧 特查拉
Wake up.
醒来吧
My son.
我的儿子
The time has come for you to come home...
时间到了 你是时候回家
and be reunited with me.
与我团聚了
Why?
为什么
Why didn't you bring the boy home?
为什么你不带那个男孩回家？
Why, Baba?
为什么 爸爸？
He...
他...
He was the truth I chose to omit.
我选择忽略掉这一事实
You were wrong to abandon him.
你不应该抛弃他的
I chose my people.
我选择了我的人民
I chose Wakanda.
我选择了瓦坎达
Our future depended...
我们的未来决定于...
You were wrong!
你错了！
All of you were wrong!
你们全都错了！
To turn your backs on the rest of the world!
错就错在我们对于外面的世界视而不见
We let the fear of our discovery
对外面世界的恐惧
stop us from doing what is right!
阻碍了我们做出正确的选择
No more!
不能再这样下去了！
I cannot stay here with you.
我不能和你待在这
I cannot rest while he sits on the throne.
只要他还坐在王座上我就不能安息
He is a monster of our own making.
他是我们自己创造出来的怪物
I must take the mantle back. I must!
我必须要夺回王位 我一定要！
I must right these wrongs.
我必须纠正这些错误
Do you have a blanket?
可以给我个毯子吗？
Killmonger has the full support
克尔芒戈获得了
of our military.
军队的全力支持
And he burned the garden of the Heart-Shaped Herb.
而且他还把心形草全都烧光了
Of course he did.
他当然会这么干
That's what he was trained to do.
他就是被这么训练的
His unit used to work with the CIA
他的组织曾经和中情局合作
to destabilize foreign countries.
在别国制造混乱
They would always strike at transitions of power...
他们总是在政权交替时趁人之危
like an election year, or the death of a monarch.
比如大选年 或部族首领死亡
You get control of government, the military...
他们就掌控政府 军队
- Our resources. - Right.
- 冲着我们的资源来的 - 没错
The Great Mound.
我们伟大的部落
Our vibranium, all of my designs.
我们的振金 我的发明
He will send our weapons all over the world.
他会把我们的武器送到世界各地
You must get them out of Wakanda safely.
你必须护送她们安全离开瓦坎达
- What? - What about you?
- 什么？- 那你呢？
The challenge will have to continue.
挑战必须继续
T'Challa, we will not leave Wakanda.
特查拉 我们不会离开瓦坎达的
It is my duty to keep you safe.
保护你的安全是我的责任
If he gets control of our technology,
如果他掌控了我们的技术
nowhere will be safe.
我们无处可逃
The Black Panther lives.
黑豹还活着
And when he fights for the fate of Wakanda...
而等他为瓦坎达的命运战斗时
I will be right there beside him.
我将在他身边
As will I.
我也是
I'm in, too.
我也加入
What? You're gonna need all the help you can get.
怎么 人多力量大嘛
Are you done?
你们完事了没？
你们到底完事了没有？
Could you give me and Lord M'Baku a moment?
可以让我跟姆巴库首领单独谈谈吗？
Thank you.
谢谢你
I owed you a great debt.
我欠你的
A life for a life.
一命抵一命
Consider it paid.
你我就两清了
Please allow my mother to stay here.
请允许我母亲留在你这里
No harm will come to her. I give you my word.
她不会有事的 我向你保证
You know, I could use an army as well.
你知道 我也能带兵打仗的
I bet you could.
你当然能
But no.
但没门
I will give no Jabari lives towards your cause.
我不会让贾巴里人为你的事卖命
It is our cause.
这是我们的事
- It is for all of us. - Oh, us?
- 是我们共同的事 - 我们？
Us? You are the first king to come here in centuries...
我们？你是几个世纪以来第一个来我们这的王
and now you speak of "us"?
现在你跟我说 “我们”？
I cannot speak for past kings.
我无法替先王们开脱
But an enemy sits on the throne right now.
但如今一个敌人正坐在王位上
We both know the power of vibranium.
你我都知道振金的威力
If Killmonger gains control of it,
如果克尔芒戈掌控了它
who do you think he will come for next?
你觉得他下一个会找上谁？
We will not help you.
我们不会帮你
Everything is on schedule.
一切都在按计划进行
Have the spies been alerted?
间谍们都接到通知了吗？
Yes. Some resistance to our new mission.
是的 有一些间谍对于我们的新任务表示反对
But the War Dogs in London,
但伦敦 纽约 和香港的间谍组织
New York and Hong Kong are standing by.
都随时待命
We'll strike there first.
我们先攻打那些地方
The others'll come around.
其他人会审时度势的
Look at this.
看看这个
A handheld sonic cannon,
这个手持超音速炮的威力
powerful enough to stop a tank...
足以对抗坦克
untraceable by metal detectors.
金属探测器都追查不到
And we got thousands of them.
而且我们有几千个
The world's gonna find out exactly who we are.
世界终将明白我们的真正实力
He lives.
他还活着
N'Jadaka!
尼•贾达卡
Wassup?
你想怎样？
I never yielded!
我还没投降！
And as you can see, I am not dead!
而且如你所见 我也没死！
All that challenge shit is over with!
挑战什么的已经结束了
I'm the king now!
现在我是王
Get those planes in the air! Carry out the mission!
让飞机起飞 继续任务
- Shuri, now. - Copy that.
- 舒莉 就现在 - 收到
Go, go, go! Come on, Ross!
快走  快走 快点 罗斯
W'Kabi, man, kill this clown.
瓦卡比 干掉这只小丑
W'Kabi, the challenge is not complete.
瓦卡比 挑战还没结束
What will we do?
我们该怎么办
Border Tribe!
边疆部落
You!
你！
Your heart is so full of hatred...
你的心中怨气太深
you are not fit to be a king!
你不适合当王！
Come on!
来吧
Ayo, the king!
阿尤 保护国王
Shields!
防御阵型
W'Kabi, stop this!
瓦卡比 停下来！
Stop this now!
快停下！
No!
不！
Nakia and I will get control of the Royal Talon with this.
娜奇雅和我将会用这个控制皇家战机
So what do I do?
那么 我做什么
You'll have to fly it.
你要驾驶它
- What? - You were a great pilot.
- 什么？- 你曾是个厉害的飞行员
Don't worry, I'll guide you through it.
不用担心 我会指导你的
It's just like riding a hoverbike.
就像开摩托飞艇一样
What? You guys have hoverbikes?
什么？你们还有摩托飞艇吗？
Hey, Nakia, take that.
嘿 娜奇雅 穿上这个
- I'm not a Dora. - Just put it on, it's armor!
- 我又不是战士 - 就穿上吧 这是战甲！
Come!
快来
Good luck, Agent Ross!
祝你好运 罗斯探员
Yeah, I don't know what I'm doing with this.
我不知道该怎么用...这个东西
We're counting on you.
我们都指望你了
Wakanda forever.
瓦坎达万岁
Come on!
上啊！
Go, go!
快走
Remote piloting system activated.
远程驾驶系统启动
My God.
天啊
I made it American style for you. Get in.
我帮你改成美式机舱了 快坐进去
All right.
好吧
Yes!
好！
Go! We can't let those weapons get beyond Wakanda.
快上 我们不能让那些武器出了瓦坎达的边境
All right, I'm on it.
好的 我马上
Lock!
锁住！
Get him down!
拿下
Get the necklace!
摘掉他的项链
摘掉他的项链！
Wakanda forever!
瓦坎达万岁！
Okay, Shuri. I got 'em. What do I do?
好了 舒莉 我追到他们了 我该怎么做？
Shoot them down, genius!
把他们打下来啊 天才！
All right.
好吧
Here goes nothing.
我尽力而为吧
All right, got them.
好了 一架
Oh, shit.
该死
Shit, shit, shit.
Nice!
漂亮
Shuri!
舒莉！
What's up, Princess?
怎么了 公主？
You'll never be a true king.
你永远成不了真正的王
Brother!
哥哥！
Shuri.
舒莉
Brother!
哥哥！
Turn on the train on the bottom track.
把最底下的火车开起来
The stabilizers will deactivate your suit!
稳定器会让你的战衣失效的的
You won't have protection!
你到时候就没有保护了
Neither will he.
那他也不会有
Okay!
好吧
I don't need a suit to kill you.
我根本不需要这身衣服来杀你
Your reign is over!
你的统治结束了
You sat up here, safe and protected.
你以为你能稳居王位
You want to see us become
你就是想看着我们
just like the people you hate so much.
变成那些你憎恨的人一样
Divide and conquer the land as they did!
就像那些殖民者一样
Nah, I learn from my enemies. Beat them at they own game.
不 这是我从敌人那儿学到的 以牙还牙
You have become them!
你已经变得跟他们一样！
You will destroy the world, Wakanda included!
你会毁了这世界的 包括瓦坎达在内
The world took everything away from me!
这个世界夺走了我的一切！
Everything I ever loved!
一切我所爱的东西！
But I'mma make sure we're even.
但是我会确保人人平等
I'mma track down anyone who would
我要找到所有
even think about being loyal to you!
哪怕对你只有一丝忠诚的人！
And I'm gonna put they ass in the dirt
全都宰了埋了
right next to Zuri!
就埋在祖瑞的边上！
Nakia!
娜奇雅！
- Are you all right? - I'm okay. You?
- 你没事吧？- 我没事 你呢？
- Yes. - Let's go.
- 没事 - 我们走
Shuri, I've lost one of them, but two are on my tail.
舒莉 我甩掉了一架敌机 但是还有两架在我屁股后面
Shit. What the hell was that?
什么鬼？
The lab is under attack.
实验室正遭受攻击
What? Where?
什么？哪？
Deactivating hologram.
停止全息影像
Ross, you have to get out of there, now!
罗斯 你必须马上离开那
How long have I got?
我还剩多久时间？
Glass integrity is at 50%.
玻璃完整度 50%
Put me back in.
把我接回去
Ross! Ross!
罗斯！罗斯！
Surrender now!
马上投降！
You have three seconds to lay down your weapon!
你有三秒钟放下你的武器
One!
一！
Two!
二！
Witness the might of the Jabari firsthand!
让你们见识见识贾巴里的力量吧！
Glass integrity is at 15%.
玻璃完整度 15%
- Critical weapons failure. - Shit!
- 武器严重损毁 - 该死
Hey, Shuri! The last cargo ship
舒莉 最后一艘货船
is almost at the border...
就快到边境了
but they got me trapped with some kind of cables.
他们现在用某种电缆把我困住了
Make an X with your arms!
把双手交叉放在胸前
Sonic Overload initiated.
音速超频启动
Now break it!
现在 放开
System rebooting in five...
五秒后重启系统...
four, three...
4 3
two, one.
2 1
System rebooted.
系统重启完成
Yes! We did it!
耶！ 我们成功了！
Great! Now get out of there!
太好了 现在赶紧离开那
Charge!
冲
Drop your weapon!
放下你的武器
Would you kill me, my love?
你会杀了我吗 亲爱的？
For Wakanda?
为了瓦坎达？
Without question!
毫无疑问
This is it for you, Cousin.
到此为止了 堂哥
Hell of a move!
有两下子啊
My pop said Wakanda was
爸爸说
the most beautiful thing he ever seen.
瓦坎达是他见过最美丽的地方
He promised he was gonna show it to me one day.
他答应我 说总有一天他会带我去看看
You believe that?
你能相信吗
Kid from Oakland,
一个奥克兰的小屁孩
running around believing in fairy tales.
整天活在童话故事里
It's beautiful.
真的很美
Maybe we can still heal you.
也许我们还能治好你
Why?
为什么？
So you can just lock me up?
然后你就可以把我关起来？
Nah.
才不要
Just bury me in the ocean...
把我葬在海里
with my ancestors that jumped from the ships.
就像我那些从船上跳海的先祖们一样
'Cause they knew death was better than bondage.
因为他们知道死也比被奴役好
Thank you.
谢谢
You saved me.
你救了我
You saved my family.
你救了我的家人
Our nation.
我们的国家
There's nothing to thank me for.
你不用谢我什么
It is our duty to...
这是我们的...
It was my duty to fight for what I love.
为我爱的事物去战斗是我的义务
I should've...
我就应该...
You can't blame me, I almost died.
你不能怪我 我差点就死了
Stay.
留下
I think I know a way
我想我有个办法
you can still fulfill your calling.
仍可以让你实现你的愿望
Please stay.
留下吧
Oh, he moves it! He moves it!
他要上篮了 他要上篮了
- Who man is that? - Bucket!
- 谁负责防守他的 - 进了
Easy.
小菜一碟
When you said you would take me
你之前说
to California for the first time...
要带我到加州
I thought you meant Coachella...
我还以为你指的是让我参加科切拉音乐节
or Disneyland.
或者是迪士尼乐园
Why here?
为什么是这里？
This is where our father killed our uncle.
这就是我们的父亲杀了我们叔叔的地方
They're tearing it down.
这里要被拆掉了
Good.
很好
They are not tearing it down.
这里不会被拆掉的
I bought this building.
我买下了这栋楼
And that building.
还有那栋
And that one over there.
以及那边那栋
This will be the first
这里将成为第一个
Wakandan International Outreach Center.
瓦坎达国际援助中心
Nakia will oversee the social outreach.
娜奇雅会负责监管社会援助
And you will spearhead
而你会负责进行
the science and information exchange.
第一次科学与信息交流活动
You're kidding.
你在逗我吗
Eh?
有吗？
Hey, yo. Man, what the hell is that?
嘿 哥们 那是什么
That's like a Bugatti spaceship!
这是布加迪牌的宇宙飞船吧
Bro, it came out of nowhere. Did y'all see that?
就这么凭空出现了 你看到了吗？
What?
什么？
Check it out, bro.
快来看啊
We can take this back to the house.
把这个带回家呀
Pull up to school in this.
开着这个去上学啊
Look, we can break it apart. We can sell it. On eBay.
嘿 听着 我们可以把这个给拆了然后卖掉 在易贝上卖
eBay （易贝）一个管理可让全球民众上网买卖物品的线上拍卖及购物网站  1995
年9月4日创立于加利福尼亚州圣荷西 人们可以在ebay上通过网络出售商品 eBay
及其原先拥有的PayPal类似国内淘宝和支付宝  一个用于开店 一个用于付款
Everybody get, like, a million apiece.
一片就能卖上个几十万
I wouldn't do that if I were you guys.
我如果是你们我就不会这么做
- Where you come from? - From Wakanda.
- 你从哪来的？- 瓦坎达
What is a Wakanda?
瓦坎达是哪？
Hey, yo!
嘿 你！
This yours?
这是你的？
Who...
你...
Who are you?
你是谁？
黑 豹
联合国总部
奥地利       维也纳
My name is King T'Challa...
我是国王特查拉
son of King T'Chaka.
特查卡国王之子
I am the sovereign ruler of the nation of Wakanda.
我是瓦坎达的最高统治者
And for the first time in our history...
这是我们有史以来第一次
we will be sharing our knowledge and resources...
与外界分享交流
with the outside world.
我们的知识和资源
Wakanda will no longer watch from the shadows.
瓦坎达不再会置身于幕后
We cannot.
我们不能
We must not.
我们也不应该
We will work to be an example of how we...
我们将努力成为一个榜样
as brothers and sisters on this earth...
向世人展示 如何像对待兄弟姐妹一样
should treat each other.
对待地球上的同胞
Now, more than ever...
今昔不比往日
the illusions of division threaten our very existence.
分裂的假象威胁着我们的存在
We all know the truth.
我们都知道真相
More connects us than separates us.
我们的共同点远大于我们的分歧点
But in times of crisis...
但是在危机时刻
the wise build bridges...
智者将建立桥梁
while the foolish build barriers.
而愚者则建立高墙
We must find a way...
我们必须达成共识
to look after one another...
同舟共济
as if we were one, single tribe.
构建人类命运共同体
With all due respect, King T'Challa...
恕我直言 国王特查拉
what can a nation of farmers
你们一个农耕国家
have to offer the rest of the world?
能向全世界贡献什么呢？
Are you playing around with that man again?
你们又在那个人的旁边胡闹吧
- No. - You're teasing him again.
- 没有 - 你又在逗他了
- Don't wake him. He must rest. - No, I'm not.
- 别吵醒他 他需要休息 - 我没有
No, I'm not.
我没有
Thabo, you're doing that.
塔博 就是你干的
He's doing it. He's lying.
是他干的 他撒谎
No, he's resting.
不要闹了 他在休息呢
Go, go!
去玩吧
White Wolf!
白狼
Stop that!
别闹了
White Wolf!
白狼
巴基•巴恩斯 冬日战士（Winter Soldier） 漫威漫画旗下超级英雄 美国队长史蒂夫•罗杰斯
在二战中最亲密的战友和最坚实的后盾 后来在二战尾声的一次行动中  与队长一同掉入大海
之中被冰封 在美队3中冬兵因为被洗脑一只手被钢铁侠打断 之后恢复记忆后遭到追杀被黑豹
所拯救 带到了瓦坎达进行治疗  苏醒的冬兵  邪恶的记忆应该已经被清除
Good morning, Sergeant Barnes.
早上好 巴恩斯中士
Bucky.
叫我巴基就行
How are you feeling?
你感觉如何
Good.
挺好的
Thank you.
谢谢你
Come.
跟我来
Much more for you to learn.
你要学的东西还有很多
黑豹将重返《复仇者联盟：无限战争》